Andrey Marchenko

Senior backend developer

Location: Berlin, Germany

E-Mail: anvmarchenko@gmail.com

Enthusiastic web developer with experience in enterprise, startups and open source projects. I enjoy solving challenging tasks and creating great products making peoples' life better. Being a fan of reliable and easy-to-change projects, I strive to make the code in my projects as clean and tested as possible. Besides my main work, I develop my side project in which my passions for travel and creation are combined.

Keywords

- Ruby on Rails (RSpec, Capybara)
- Elixir/Phoenix
- Javascript, Angularis, React, HTML5, CSS
- Java 8
- Postgresql, Mongodb
- Elasticsearch
- Docker, Ansible
- Vagrant
- Git

Communication

- Russian (native)
- English (full working proficiency)
- German (limited working proficiency)

Work experience

FinReach, Senior developer

January 2015 - present

As one of the first developers in the company, performed full cycle of development for several company's internal and external products including automated bank account switch kit, which is one of the most innovative and modern products in banking area in Germany.

- Full-stack development of several products using Ruby on Rails, Angularjs and Mongodb
- Implemented automated unit and integration testing for a number of projects
- Integrated Elasticsearch as main search index to scale quickly growing project
- Participated in development of service oriented architecture

- Performed a number of refactorings to ensure code cleanliness and testability
- Worked hand to hand with product managers and design teams to provide all necessary technical support in defining product vision and strategy

AT Consulting, Expert developer

April 2011 - January 2015

AT Consulting is one of the leading consulting and enterprise software developers in Russia. I worked as lead developer on several enterprise level, nationwide projects for government customers.

- Performed full-stack development of Java and Ruby on Rails applications
- Provided third level of support for partners and customers
- Created enterprise level integration layers using Java and ActiveMQ
- Helped operations team to troubleshoot production environment issues
- Coordinated distributed team of developers
- Closely interacted with system analysts and QA teams to define roadmap and vision of the projects and ensure high product quality

Projects

Automated account switch kit

One of the first european products for fully automated bank account switch. Using intelligent transaction analysis it allows customers transfer their direct debits, incoming payments, standing orders and remaining balance to new bank account. I am performing development for client-facing services as well as a number of internal services. In order to ensure high product quality and stability, I am doing regular code reviews and performing refactorings. Constantly working on scaling product to adequately respond to growing load.

Document Management System for Ministry of Internal Affairs

Nationwide system used by internal affairs offices all over Russia for registering and processing documents. Built using service oriented architecture and consists of dozens of services as well as several integration layers. As one of the first and key developers on this project, I developed client-facing services and integration layers of this system. During work on this project I developed ERB-based DSL for generating docx documents from rails code.

Federal Electronic Registry for Ministry of Healthcare

National medical registry allows patients in Russia to book doctor appointments online by connecting them with hundreds of clinics. I was responsible for developing Java based integration layer connecting client web application with clinics' systems. Integration was done using SOAP and HL7 protocols. I worked closely with our integration partners providing them support and all necessary documentation in order to achieve integration goals.

State services portal

Gosuslugi.ru is main online entry point for receiving state services in Russian Federation. I developed client forms using Java and Spring MVC and performed troubleshooting of production environment issues.

Education

Pskov State Polytechnical Institute

September 2006 - June 2011

Specialist degree in Computing machines, systems, complexes and networks